Umair Lakhiar

♦ Karachi, Sindh, Pakistan
Image: Sindh of the control of the co

🛅 https://www.linkedin.com/in/umair-lakhiar/ 🕳 https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Umair-Lakhiar

SUMMARY

A task-focused and conscientious individual capable of supporting and giving effective recommendations for devising strategies for various Human Resource functional areas related to Recruitment and Talent Acquisition database management, resources employee development to boost service efficiency and organizational effectiveness to achieve optimum performance and revenue goals.

Ex-cadet, Petarian and a passionate business graduate. Worked on project SUCCESS funded by European Union.

EXPERIENCE

HR Executive and Administration Officer 7C Tech

December 2022 - Present, Karachi Pakistan

- · Onboarded 20 plus employees in 3 months.
- · Documented all 40 employees online.
- Developed attendance tracker system, salary slips, experience certificates etc. and updated formats.
- Shortlisted candidates by having telephonic interview.
- · Identified appropriate candidates and assessed their qualifications through review of their resumes, interviews, and other forms of communications.
- · Collected data of employees through google forms.
- Tagged office laptop systems for record maintenance.
- · Answered queries by employees and vendors.
- Communicated vendors for required services in office premises.

Team Lead Recruitment

RippleMatch

September 2022 - February 2023, Remote

- · Sourced all candidates through LinkedIn Recruiter.
- · Correspondence and communication with the candidates.
- Shortlisting the promising students.
- Matching them with relevant positions in our client's Portfolio.
- · Leaded team of 15 Recruitment specialists remotely.

Administration Officer

Thardeep Rural Development Programme (TRDP)

March 2020 - June 2022, Jamshoro Sindh

- $\cdot \ \, \text{Check and verify the accuracy and correctness of the amount and other details of utility bills/invoices} \\ \, \text{received from service providers} \\$
- Preparing Documentations like Memos, Fuel average sheets purchase requests (PR) and issuing Goods receiving notes (GRN)
- Process and implement contracts for office services
- · Monitoring district vehicles ensuring their proper fueling and maintenance
- · Kept and updated employees records (physical and digital)
- · Monitored and updated attendance in Software at the district level and Timesheet of employees at field units
- Arranged monthly review meetings

- · Per diem claiming for employees to whom assigned additional duty
- · Supervised support staff and monitored work processes

Office Coordinator

Cyberxify

September 2018 - February 2020, Karachi Pakistan

- · Interacted with visitors and vendors.
- · Served visitors by greeting/welcoming and directing them appropriately.
- · Managed incoming and outgoing calls daily.
- · Attendance register maintained and updated records.
- · Photocopied, scanned, and filed appropriate documents.
- · Sustained responsibility for office maintenance where and whenever required.

EDUCATION

Master of Business Administration (HR)

Igra University · Karachi · 2023

Bachelor of Business Administration

Iqra University · Karachi · 2019

Intermediate (Pre-Engineering)

Cadet College Petaro · Jamshoro · 2014

CERTIFICATIONS

HR and Digital Transformation

Society for Human Resource Management • 2021

Handling Workplace Bullying

Helping People and Organizations Excel • 2021

Strategic Thinking

Project Management Institute • 2021

COURSEWORK

Examining the effect of Innovation and Leadership on the Performance of Enterprises SMEs in Pakistan

Igra University • 2023

Factors effecting brand relationships on social media platforms

Iqra University • 2019

SKILLS

Recruitment: Screening, Shortlisting

MS Office: Microsoft Excel, Microsoft Word

Administration: Team Management, Internal Controls, Fleet Management, Forecasting, Transportation/Pick and Drop, Logbooks, Service Books, Purchase Request/Orders, Service Orders

HRIS: Management, Reporting, Documentation, Talent Acquision